Christopher LLOYD

- SF Bay Area CA
- (510) 517-2097
- chrislloyd@me.com
- github.com/chrislloyd
- in linkedin.com/in/chlloyd
- <u>iChristopher.net</u>

EDUCATION

University of California Berkeley

Berkeley CA | UX/UI Design | Graphic Design / Computer Programing

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Sloan School of
Management
Cambridge MA
| Executive Leadership
Program: Business Process
Design for Strategic
Management

Dale Carnegie

San Mateo | Leadership Training for Managers

Mesa Community College

Mesa AZ | General Studies

SUMMARY

Solutions-savvy and passionate UX/UI Designer combining creativity and usability viewpoints to design, web and mobile applications. Passionate about visual design, collaboration and creating the ultimate user experience.

Motivational and inspirational leader in creating world-class work environments and culture within an organization where team members are inspired to do their life's best work.

PROJECTS

Case Study: Communication for Global Innovation (CFGI) | Link to Project

- A complete website redesign; our stakeholders couldn't wait to implement our design
 - o Core Responsibilities: Research, Testing, Content writing, IA
 - Secondary Responsibilities: Visual Design, Prototyping

Case Study: The City of Palo Alto | Link to Project

- A website redesign focused on overall navigation and creation of a new "Community" section. We brought this very boring government site into the mainstream with a fun & creative design that captures the spirit of Palo Alto.
 - o Core Responsibilities: Research, Testing, Content writing, IA
 - Secondary Responsibilities: Visual Design, Prototyping

Case Study: Mobile App and Website Landing Page: ExRemedy | Link to Project

- A class project to create a mobile app and (RWD) web landing page
 - Core Responsibilities: Front End Development (FED), RWD for landing page, Research, Testing
 - Secondary Responsibilities: IA, Content Writing, Visual Design, Prototyping,

EXPERIENCE

UX / UI Product Designer | Remote

iChritopher Design

(2020-Present)

- Completed 3 case study projects using the design thinking process with front end development
- Led specific areas in the design thinking process methodology on 3 case studies in the UC Berkeley UX/UI design school

Inspirion Inc. | CA

INDEPENDENT CONSULTANT/ENTREPERNEUR

(2015-Present)

- Venture X: Investor/Managing Partner in Commercial Real Estate Startup
 - Partnered with Cushman & Wakefield for commercial real estate property locations in the SF Bay Area
 - Research and development for Bay Area commercial real estate in conjunction with United Franchise Group
 - Completed 5-year financial projections on multiple locations for coworking office space
- $oldsymbol{\emptyset}$ Guardian Harvest: Investor/Managing Partner in Agricultural Startup
 - Analyzed data to improve operations, built analytical framework and operational models to enable scalability and sustainability for domestic and international

SKILLS

Research:

Persona, Archetype, Research Plan, User Research, Interview, Survey, Data Analysis, Interpret Data, Strategy, Guerilla Testing, User Testing, Competitor Analysis, SWOT

Ideation:

Affinity Diagram, Empathy Map, User Scenario, Storyboarding, Journey Mapping, Prioritization Matrix, User Flow, Sketching, Wireframing, Moodboard, Prototyping

Visual:

Drawing, Sketching, Vector, Video Editing, UX/UI, Motion, Interaction, Micro Interaction, Design Systems, Graphic Design, Print, Typography, Accessibility, Color Theory, Data Visualization

Front End Development:

HTML 5, CSS 3, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GitHub, VScode, Atom, BB Edit, Webflow, Mobirise, Responsive Web Design (RWD), Hotjar, Google Analytics

Tools:

Figma, Miro, InVision, Trello, Adobe XD PS IA, Google Suite, MS Office

Leadership:

Successfully led large teams with 500+ employees in my direct organization

- Created strategic plan for recruitment and retention of a highly talented and diverse team of professionals and support staff
- Provided training and development to managers and supervisors to work strategically, set priorities, define goals and outcomes, detail tactics, and achieve results.
- Managed multiple projects with leadership team to plan, design, construct the marketing strategy to grow and generate new contracts
- Renegotiated all contracts with stakeholders to multi-year vs annual

Apple Inc. | Cupertino, CA MARKET LEADER

(2002-2014)

- Promoted through multiple progressive leadership roles (General Manager, New Store Opening Manager, Store Manager, Assistant Store Manager) to Market Manager, leading multi-unit high-profile retail stores in Silicon Valley, 500+ employees generating \$225M/annually. On elite team of eight Market Leaders with VP that built strategy for 36 stores (3500+ employees) and \$1.1B in annual sales.
- Oversaw all facets of business, i.e. P&L, sales forecast, payroll, talent acquisition, HR decision/collaboration, performance management, sales/leadership training, inventory, system/resource planning, reporting, travel budget and expense account
- Improved operational excellence through identification and execution of
 initiatives that create efficiency, remove obstacles, or create improved
 processes and approaches to the business, including the identification of
 various tools to build and deploy improved workflows and Inspired team to
 deliver experiences that built customer loyalty
- Analyzed key metrics, including customer and employee feedback to provide and ensure the quality experience for each customer entering the Apple Store
- Ensured to that multiple locations remained aligned, while executing organizational initiatives to contribute to the future success of Apple
- Support sales teams on medium/long-term planning including deep analytics of business potential
- Identify, scope and drive critical projects and initiatives for Business & Sales

 Measurement, partnering with cross-functional teams across the organization
- Training and development: worked alongside field staff in selling as well as teaching, to help team members as needed